Sadisha Galappatti

SOFTWARE ENGINEER · CSM, SECURITY ENTHUSIAST

□ (+1) 289-339-2717 | Sadishag@gmail.com | # www.sadishagalappatti.ca | • sadishag | • sadishag

Summary_

Software Engineer in Training currently working at RBC on the API Platform. 2+ years of work experience with backend/infrastructure, web development and security and experience being a tech lead in a small team. I know my way around a unix like terminal and love to build out my perfect development environment. The hard challenges keep me motivated and moving forward. Constantly on the search for opportunities to grow personally and professionally.

SKILLS: Python, Java, NodeJS, Angular, Ansible, Bash, HTML/CSS, Golang, Ruby on Rails, C/C++, C#, MySQL, Redis, Cassandra, Postgres, Elastic-search, Logstash, Kibana, Apigee, PCF

Work Experience _____

RBC Toronto, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER | TECHNICAL LEAD

June 2017 - Present

- · Architected and deployed the API Gateway platform within a time period of 4 months (https://developer.rbc.com)
- Ensured full scalability and security of the platform during implementation and automated operational/CI/CD tasks using Ansible, Jenkins, Python and Github
- Increased turnaround time to engage and integrate external partnerships for the entire bank by 50%
- · Reduced number of rollbacks by implementing efficient, automated deployment processes
- · Managed engagement, education and onboarding to the API Platform and developed standards around usage
- Managed and maintained the infrastructure to run the API Gateway platform to allow for a 99.999% up time SLA and lead the push for an in production zero downtime upgrade of the platform
- Enabled Oauth and Mutual Authenticaion (2waySSL) as generic policy to add to API's. Policies are now used in 300+ API's at RBC
- Developing a redesigned version of the developer portal using Angular and Golang
- · Developed a CI/CD process to push compiled Angular build artifacts to PCF using Jenkins and NodeJS
- · Worked collaboratively with various teams to aid with architecure, security and general problem solving
- Contributor to various internal open-source (innersource) projects at RBC
- KEY ACHIEVEMENTS: RBC Digital Q3 2018 Team Award, Top Performance Rating for 2 years in a row

Blackberry Limited Waterloo, Canada

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER INTERN

Sept. 2015 - Aug. 2016

- Built restful API's (Ruby on Rails) following a microservice architecture as part of a 2.0 deployment of BlackBerry CloudConsole application
- Dashboard development such as chargeback data pull, OS level patch monitoring, KAFKA/GRAFANA integration
- Developed on top of an asset tracking configuration management platform
- Created and delivered introduction courseware outlining the adoption process of CMDB tool

McMaster University

Hamilton, Canada

COMPUTER SOFTWARE ASSISTANT

May. 2015 - Aug. 2015

Developed tools for researchers to automate genome sequencing task such as converting FASTQ or fna to FASTA files

- Rebuilt lab website using WordPress for ease of use
- Optimized current bioinformatics website for performance increases
- Used RossettaPy in the development of a tool to create 3D models of protein sequences

Program Committees

2013 - Pres Technical/Youth Board Member, Wellwood Cancer Centre

Hamilton, Canada

Education

McMaster University

B.Eng. IN SOFTWARE ENGINEERING

Hamilton, Canada

Class of 2017

December 19, 2018 Sadisha D. Galappatti · Résumé